Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computer Science and

Notice Period: 1 Month

Information Security]



Sr. Software Developer / Full Stack Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Business Intelligence, Resource Allocation, Quality Management, Business Development, CSS, Javascript



Current Designation: Sr. Software Developer / Full Stack

Developer

Current Company: Operative

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Sr. Software Developer / Full Stack Developer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Business Intelligence, Resource Allocation, Quality

Management, Business Development, CSS, Javascript

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Currently working with Operative, Bangalore, KA as Sr. Software Developer

Successfully worked on various major projects such as HPE Oneview, Nutrisystem, Nutrinet, PTA (Promotion Tracking Application), South Beach Diet & NBC

Proficiency in designing, developing & producing various NBC Modules, which were successfully implemented by Operative Expertise in managing client network security through installation of firewalls & VPNs; track record in installing appropriate security patches to dissolve security vulnerabilities

Excellence in updating network systems to support confidential company operations & eliminating hacking ability Strategist in liaising with third-party development team on engineering & professional service activities & tasks

Work Experience

Operative as Sr. Software Developer / Full Stack Developer Nov 2019 to Till Date

Key Result Areas:

Gathering & analyzing requirement; discussing with the client NBC O&O for the creation of story in JIRA

Managing domain clarification & technical approach; finalizing story points for all stories for particular sprint to complete implementation and deliver the requirements timely

Liaised with Client NBC O&O on the daily basis to report the progress of sprint

Conducted sprint retrospective with internal team members after completion of each sprint to self-inspect and create a plan for improvements to be enacted during the next Sprint

Presented the Demo to client along with other modules after completion of every release (3 sprints)

Hewlett Packard Enterprise as Sr. Software Developer

Apr 2018 to Nov 2019

Key Result Areas:

Gathered requirement to understand the requirements & to translate the requirement to stories also the time required to

complete the stories for each sprint

Developed the pages as per mocks given by UX developers using front-end technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, MVP architecture followed by the HP Team

Used GIT as a version control & eclipse as a tool to develop front-end pages

Generated testcases & mocks for pages developed using Qunit to make sure all modules are working as per

Conducted daily sprint meetings to get the know status; informed other members in team to stay sync with each other Presented the demo at the end of the sprint to get it reviewed by all the members in the team

Interfaced with testing team regarding the process & development task; fixed bugs if any given by testing team

Formulated boardroom & courtroom multimedia presentations including video & text- sync'd depositions for enhanced understanding

NuWare Systems LLP as Software Developer

Jan 2017 to Aug 2018

Key Result Areas:

Gathered requirement & communicated with the client in order to develop the mocks Developed:

- Low level design using Jiffy tool for POC in order to demonstrate to client
- Pages as per the mocks given using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Angular JS & wrote test cases using Qunit
- Responsive design pages using Bootstrap & Media Queries; verified pages in browser stack & real hardware devices Pushed the development task to various environment (CI, DI, Stage, Production) by verifying all the flows in each of the environment and also sending the report to all the members in the team as well as client

Fixed the bugs given the testing team in various environment (CI, DI, Stage, Production)

Updated the status to client during sprint meetings held daily and took inputs from other members as well as clients in order to stay in sync with each other

Communicated with testing team to discuss the flow; generated the test cases for various testing environment

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2014

PG: M.Tech (Computer Science and Information Security) from Manipal Institute of Technology (MIT) in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	ed Experience	
Windows 7, Unix		2017	3 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
MS SQL 2008, Visual Studio 2008		2016	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Eclipse, Photoshop CS3		2017	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap		2017	3 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
JQUERY		2017	3 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
Angular	4	2017	1 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Kannada	Expert			
Telugu	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: NBC Operative

Client: NBC

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: NBC is a American News Channel where we need to show the TRP rating of each and every stations in the New York City So that it will be helpful for the advertisement companies to decide about the posted of adds in a TV Channel

based the analysis of the ratings provided for each and every program in a chanels.

Project Title: One View

Client: Hewlett Packard Enterprise Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Mar 2017 - Nov 2017

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: OneView is the Network Monitoring Application responsible for managing the servers in the HP organization

Project Title: Nutrinet Client: Nutrisysten

Duration: Dec 2015 - Jan 2017 Nature of Employment: Full Time

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Nutrinet is the back office application for the nutrisytem. where the user can call to the call center in order to

order the weight loss and diabetic people.

The call center has the option to delay, drop and update the order.

Project Title: Nutrisytem Client: Nutrisystem

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2014 - Mar 2017

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Nutrisytem is the E-commerce Application where the user can purchase the weight loss and diabetic products

as per the guidence given by the doctors.

The user has the provision update ,delete, drop the order as per the convince

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: OBC - non-creamy Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time